[Music]
[音乐]
翻译，压制：旋火
视频来源：youtu.be/XmxB6gTo2pI
We've just stepped inside Rosie the robot.
我们刚刚进入了机器人Rosie
Rocket Labs newest piece of automation equipment.
火箭实验室最新的一个自动化设备
This machine as you can see is absolutely massive.
你能看到这台机器很大
You can literally Park a school bus on this.
在这上面能容纳下一个校巴
It's that big.
就是那么大
What this machine does is it takes every single carbon composite component of the launch vehicle
这台机器所做的事是把火箭每个部分的碳复合材料
and processes it ready to move on to the next stage of production.
进行处理 并进行下一阶段的生产
Now what Rosie really means her Rocket Lab in our launch frequency
对于Rocket Lab(火箭实验室)而言 Rosie的意义在于提升发射频率
is they're able to process launch vehicles so much faster.
使得处理火箭的速度变得更快
Traditionally you talk about rocket manufacturing in years.
一般来讲 生产火箭的周期按年计算
Then start talking about it in months, weeks.
后来开始按月 按星期计算
Well, we talked about it in the days.
而我们现在按天计算
Raw materials come in.
原材料进来了
Rocket comes out in a matter of hours.
几小时之内 火箭就出去了
So that's every bit of marking, every bit of machining, every bit of drilling.
每一点儿标记 加工 钻孔
All the operations you can imagine.
所有你能想象的操作
It literally takes hundreds of hours
(不用机器的时候)真的要花几百个小时
and we can produce one launch vehicle in this machine every 12 hours.
现在我们用这个机器生产一枚火箭只要12小时
What you see here is a second stage of Electron
你在这里看到是电子的二级
getting the final post processing completed on it.
完成了最终的后处理
Ready to ship out to the production line.
准备送往生产线
[Music]
[音乐]